

# Kassem Itani

Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, Riyadh, Kharis Rd, Al-Rayan, Qatr Al-Nada St.

Phone: +966 (54) 785 7521 E-Mail: kassem.itani@gmail.com Website: www.Kassemitani.com

LinkedIn Profile: http://lb.linkedin.com/in/kassemitani/

### **Summary**

Results oriented IT professional with 6-year experience in IOS & Android application development, testing, troubleshooting, and implementation working for leading retail and technology enterprises. Excel at analysis, problem solving and technical leadership to deliver mobile applications with great user experience. Expert communication, interpersonal, and organizational skills.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Fluent understanding of agile project management and software development life cycle (SDLC).
- iOS Development-Excellent working knowledge of Xcode, Swift, Objective-C, SQLite
- Android Development-Excellent working knowledge of Eclipse and Android Studio/Gradle, Java, SQLite
- Experienced with MS SharePoint.
- Excellent analysis skills and the ability to develop processes and methodologies
- Able to craft stable, well documented code within a complex application environment.
- Able to write clear technical documentation & specifications.

## **Experience**

# Lead Mobile App Architect | eMCREY Solutions Inc. (Riyadh, KSA) Jul 2017 - Present

- Designed and developed advanced native digital banking apps for iOS and Android platforms
- Developed mobile NFC payment app for the Saudi market (MadaPay).
- Requirements gathering, Project analysis, software architecture, and database design.
- Writing technical documentation and specifications while maintaining a well-documented code.
- Managing delivering project according to the deadlines discussed with the product team

# Lead Mobile App Developer | Al Ahli Holding Group

(Dubai, UAE) Mar 2016 — Jul 2017

- Design and build advanced native e-commerce apps for iOS and Android platforms
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship native iOS and android apps
- Requirements gathering, Project analysis, software architecture, and database design.

## Technical Manager | MojoTribe FZ-LLC

(Dubai, UAE) Jan 2015 - Mar 2016

- Developed several mobile apps for Carrefour GCC, that includes consumer and enterprise apps.
- Provide technical training to teams when required and serve as a technical mentor to team members
- Ensure teams follow the correct procedures, policies and documentation requirements across project phases
- Guide the team through the development, testing and implementation stages and review the completed work effectively
- Provide direction and technical expertise in design, development and systems integration
- Make quick decisions and solve technical problems to provide an efficient environment for project implementation

#### Mobile Application Developer | WextWise S.A.L (Beirut, Lebanon) Aug 2012 - Dec 2014

- Used Native Objective-C and Java to develop state-of-art mobile applications for IOS, Android, Blackberry and J2ME.
- Created a mobile messaging app using TCP connection SSL encrypted.
- Involved at every project phase, from concept creation to app store deployment.
- Responsible for general maintenance of application library and debugging.
- Wrote documentation on the API technical specification and implementation.
- Tested applications on device simulators and actual devices to fine-tune products.
- Supported junior members of the team, providing ongoing advice and guidance.

#### Education

# Bachelor in Information Technology

**June 2013** 

Lebanese International University - Beirut Campus



"Kassem is a dedicated professional and reliably delivers grade A work. He appreciates the "big picture" but never misses the small details in his word. His confident knowledge of what he does makes him a very reliable resource for the project. Moreover, it was a pleasure to work with him on our applications"

- Nader El Koukach, Project Manager - Customer Systems at MAF Carrefour

"Although I did not work with Kassem for long time but it is very clear that he is a talented and creative mobile developer for both Android and iOS. We worked together on a mobile application that I think has a very unique feature and he accomplish it with a very simple and yet to the point approach, very proud of working with such human being."

- Mohamed Hassanin, Development Manager, Al Ahli Holding Group, at Al Ahli Holding Group

"Since his graduate and years since then I have seen Kassem grow and flourish in the world of technology. Smart worker, hard worker, and thorough thinker. Always up to date with the latest technology. Kassem also contributes to the company from a business development perspective assisting the CEO in execution strategy and marketing. I expect Kassem to continue to excel and contribute to the business ecosystem in Lebanon."

- Rami Hajjar, CEO, at Hadzup